# **Troy Daniels**

Brunswick, VIC troydaniels.me 0450 679 207 troyaadaniels@gmail.com

Software engineer with a keen analytical mindset, and proven work ethic.

My experience includes agile development methodologies, positions of leadership, and liaising with both internal and external stakeholders.

I love all aspects of problem solving, learning, and helping others with the same.

### **EDUCATION**

Graduate Certificate in Information Technology
The University of NSW, Sydney

Dec 2013

Bachelor of Science (Mathematics)
The University of NSW, Sydney

Dec 2010

## **TECHNOLOGY & SKILL SUMMARY**

Programming: JavaScript (ES9+), React, React Native, Vue.js, jQuery, BASH, Java (Core,

Stripes). C

**Databases:** PostgreSQL **Testing:** Jest, Enzyme, Detox

**IDE:** JetBrains (IntelliJ, WebStorm, GoLand)

Version Control: Git

Operating Systems: macOS (preferred), Linux, Windows

Other: CCNA (expired)

### **EMPLOYMENT**

Software Engineer

October 2019 - Present

coreplus

South Melbourne, VIC

Team Size: 3 (one of several development teams)

- Upskilling of development team on React/ES best practice, including formalising code style and testing methodologies
- Leading the reimplementation of several legacy Classic ASP projects in React
- Personally involved with each step of SDLC, from customer interviews to product delivery

## **Lead Front End Engineer**

Jul 2017 - October 2019

Vonex Telecom

Richmond, VIC (previously Circular Quay, NSW)

Team Size: 10

- Primary technical liaison between company and ASX listed clients
- Relocated to Melbourne to assist in hiring and training for Melbourne office opening
- Lead the development of the company's new Oper8tor application (available on Google Play and Apple App Stores)
- Conducted all front-end developer interviews, including ad copy & design, initial screening and subsequent face to face assessments

## Front End Developer Online Marketing Gurus

Jun 2017 – *Nov 2017* 

Pyrmont, NSW Team Size: 3

- Worked on the implementation of a range of digital search campaigns at varying levels of complexity, in liaising with both our digital marketing team and clients
- Creation of internal tools, as well as dashboards for both internal and external reporting
- Assisted in the introduction, setup, maintenance and staff training across several new software tools and packages

## Senior SEO Team Lead Online Marketing Gurus Pyrmont, Sydney

Jan 2016 - June 2017

Team Size: 15

- Worked on the management of a portfolio of digital search campaigns, totaling
   ~\$100,000 monthly recurring revenue
- Increasingly focused on the automation of various tasks and dashboards through the writing, testing and maintenance of a variety of scripts and proprietary pieces of software

SEO Producer

Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

Web Profits

Chippendale, Sydney

Team Size: 18

- Worked on the management of a portfolio of SEO campaigns, which included the implementation of innovative organic ranking strategies.
- Cross-departmentally, worked on the launch and management of several large digital marketing campaigns, including Profilr, Meriton Serviced Apartments and Tune Hotels (Kuala Lumpur)

### MEMBERSHIPS & GROUPS

Australian Mathematical Society